It all begins... with a choice.
The Twilight Saga: Eclipse is a adventure, fantasy,
drama film directed by David Slade.
Bella once again finds herself surrounded by danger as Seattle is ravaged by a string of
mysterious killings and a malicious vampire continues her quest for revenge.
In the midst of it all, she is forced to choose between her love for Edward and her friendship with Jacob, knowing
that her decision has the potential to ignite the ageless struggle between vampire and werewolf.
With her graduation quickly approaching, Bella is confronted
with the most important decision of her life.
Bella Swan, played by Kristen Stewart.
Edward Cullen, played by Robert Pattinson.
Jacob Black, played by Taylor Lautner.
Victoria, played by Bryce Dallas Howard.
Jane, played by Dakota Fanning.
Charlie Swan, played by Billy Burke.
The Twilight Saga: Eclipse is a 2010 American vampire romantic fantasy film directed by David Slade from
a screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2007 novel Eclipse by Stephenie Meyer.
It is the sequel to The Twilight Saga: New Moon (2009) and the
third installment in The Twilight Saga film series.
The film stars Kristen Stewart, Robert Pattinson, and Taylor Lautner, reprising their
roles as Bella Swan, Edward Cullen, and Jacob Black, respectively.
Bryce Dallas Howard joins the cast as returning character Victoria, who was
previously portrayed by Rachelle Lefevre in the first two films.
In the film, Bella further explores her relationships with both Jacob and Edward as the threat of an army of
newborn vampires looms over the possibility of an alliance being formed between werewolves and vampires.
Summit Entertainment announced it had greenlit the film on February 20, 2009.
Principal photography began on August 17, in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, and
finished on October 31, with post-production beginning early the following month.
The Twilight Saga: Eclipse premiered at the Nokia Theatre in Los Angeles, California on June 24, 2010,
and was theatrically released in the United States on June 30, by Summit Entertainment.
It became the first The Twilight Saga film to be released in IMAX.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $760 million
worldwide, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2010.
Critics praised the action sequences, visual effects, Dallas Howard's performance, and Shore's musical
score, but criticized its pacing, most of the other performances, and the screenplay.
It held the record for biggest midnight opening in the United States and Canada, grossing $30.1 million, beating The
Twilight Saga: New Moon until it was surpassed by Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 (2011).
The film then scored the biggest Wednesday opening in the United States and Canada
with $68.5 million, beating Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen (2009).
The Twilight Saga: Eclipse has also become the film with the widest independent release, beating The Twilight Saga: New Moon, and the widest domestic
release, playing in 4,416 theaters, beating Iron Man 2, which released the same year until it was surpassed by Despicable Me 2 (2013).
The film received two sequels, The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 1 and The
Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 2, in 2011 and 2012, respectively.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
immortality, vampire, bite, graduation.
The tone is emotional.